Excuse me, sir.
Is this your Lamborghini?
Yeah.
And what do you do for living out here
in Dubai to be able to afford a Lamborghini?
I run a blockchain company.
You run a blockchain company?
I sure do.
What was the most amount of
money you made in a single year?
Twelve million dollars.
Many, many millions of dollars.
Could you give me a rate?
Over 50.
Over 50, Bill?
Last year it was a hundred million.
You made a hundred million dollars last year?
Is that for yourself or the business?
That's for myself.
Are you serious?
I'm serious.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I'm not a millionaire.
No?
No.
I own a billion dollar company.
You own a billion dollar company?
Yeah.
What type of business?
I run a bunch of tech companies.
What is your network?
300 million.
300 million dollars?
Yeah.
How can somebody become a billionaire in 2025?
I think...
Guys, I'm back in one of
the wealthiest cities in the entire world.
I'm in Dubai.
And today, I'm going to be going all
over the wealthiest areas in Dubai to find and
ask billionaires and the most successful business
owners in the entire city how they created
their wealth and the blueprints to
building multi-million dollar and multi-billion dollar
businesses in today's world.
So with that being said...
Let's get this video on the way.
Excuse me, sir.
Is this your Lamborghini?
Yeah.
And what do you do for living out here
in Dubai to be able to afford a Lamborghini?
Money business.
You're in the money business?
Are you in finance?
Yeah, we're in finance.
Yeah?
We're in finance.
Are you a business owner?
Yeah.
How long have you been an entrepreneur?
It's been about eight years now.
Eight years.
No.
But what's...
What's the business for?
I go all over the world interviewing
the most successful business owners for the younger
generation.
Could I get one quick minute
with you for the channel real quick?
Yeah, for sure.
Is that okay?
Over these eight years, what was the most
amount of money that you made in a single
year?
Last year, we did about $12 million turnover.
$12 million.
Do you come from a lot of money?
No, I don't.
I don't.
I don't come from a lot of money.
We were actually...
Eight years ago, we couldn't pay
rent and our rent was $1,300, right?
And I vote to myself that
I'm never coming to that point again.
So you were broke.
I was broke.
We had to sell our
wedding jewelry to pay rent, bro.
So it was a hard time.
Yeah.
It was a very hard time.
So what was that turning point to financial freedom?
I think the biggest point was me.
I never finished school.
So I was always the
black sheep of the family, right?
So I think it was in me like this
fire to prove people wrong that without having a degree,
you can still do a lot
of things that you ever wanted.
And now if you look at a lot
of like, you know, multi-millionaires in the world, most
of them, they never graduated, right?
They just hustled and they made it.
Now, as an eight-figure entrepreneur, what was
the best financial advice that you ever
received?
I always have full confidence.
I always have full control over the money.
If you don't have full control
over the money, you don't have anything.
I know a lot of guys who start a
business, they have no control over the money and they
get screwed up later on by their operators or whatever.
So obviously, I have full control over the
money, know where it's going, know where it's
coming from, and you're going
to be wildly successful at that.
Are you a good salesman?
I'm a great salesman.
Give me a masterclass on sales right here.
Masterclass on sales?
Give me your best sales advice right here
to somebody that sucks at sales and business.
Okay.
So I used to do door-to-door sales, right?
And we used to get rejections all the time.
So our whole hint was that
we have to knock on 100 doors.
And every rejection we get is a
lesson for the yes we're going to have.
So every time someone says no, they're saying
no, because now you got to learn from that
no and see, okay, where you can
get a yes at the next time.
What does it take to get a yes though?
How can somebody get the yes faster?
Are you in Dubai?
Yes.
You're in Dubai.
Awesome.
You like the weather here in Dubai?
I love the weather.
You like the vibe here in Dubai?
I love the vibe.
Would you like to own a
property here in Dubai one day?
I think so.
You think so, right?
So you get the yes, yes, yes.
And if there's a thing, you can easily
turn that I think so maybe to a yes.
So you got to ask a lot of questions.
You got to ask a lot of
yes questions, not a lot of no questions.
The more you say yes, yes, yes, there's
a high probability at the fourth or fifth time
when I do the ask, you're going to say yes.
Amateurs tell, pros ask.
Exactly.
That's it.
So what separates middle class
from wealthy people in today's world?
So let me tell you this.
When we couldn't pay rent, our rent was $1,300.
We had no Netflix subscription.
We had no Spotify.
We had no subscriptions at all, right?
Because we knew that, okay, money's tight.
We're starting a business.
We got to make it somehow.
We had no subscription.
What?
$9 to $5.
What does it do?
They'll get the money.
They'll buy this.
They'll buy that.
They'll get a subscription.
They'll get cards, debt, whatever, right?
But my mindset was, no, okay, you know what?
I have to save, save, save, invest.
And once we reach a certain threshold,
then we can get something to reward ourselves.
Up until now, bro, I have no YouTube premium, nothing.
I'd rather sit and watch ads to save money.
That's how you get rich, by saving money.
Your last message to somebody trying
to become a multimillionaire in 2025?
Man, if you have an idea, execute on that idea.
Whatever idea that is, no matter what people tell you,
there's a shit idea.
You got to execute on it.
Because here's the thing.
When you're going to have a business idea,
and you're going to tell someone about it
who has no business concept, they
will always tell you, it's risky.
This can happen.
That can happen.
Blah, blah, blah.
But when you bring that idea to someone
who actually has a business, they will tell you,
bro, go for that business.
Start that shit right now.
Because here's the thing.
If you're a fit guy, you're going
to tell people to stay fit, right?
If you're into business, you're going
to tell everyone to start a business.
That's what it is.
It depends on who you get your advice
from, not from who's able to give you advice.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for your time.
And I appreciate it.
It means a lot.
What was your name again?
James.
James Raja.
Nice to meet you, bro.
Nice to meet you, brother.
Nice to meet you.
So I'm at a valley outside of one
of the wealthiest hotels in all of Dubai.
My guy gets out of the Lamborghini years,
and he's holding like $2 million worth of
derms on him.
Guys, that's like half a million dollars in American cash.
But I want to put this in perspective.
Because like he said, a couple of
years ago, he could barely pay his rent.
It was $1,000.
And now he's making over $10 million a year.
So it just goes to show what can happen if
you sacrifice for a few years and get in the
right industry, the right money.
You make a vehicle just like him,
and you yourself can build a multi-million dollar
business.
Great interview out here in Dubai.
We got to keep this video
rolling and go get this next one.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I'm not a millionaire.
No?
No.
I own a billion dollar company.
You own a billion dollar company?
Yeah.
What type of business?
A blockchain.
How long have you been a business owner?
17 years now.
I started when I was 16.
Now I'm 34.
So 17, 18 years actually.
Yeah?
And I go all over the world
interviewing billionaires and the most successful people.
Could I get one quick minute with you real quick?
For the channel.
Sure.
How long did it take you
to build a billion dollar company?
Started in April of 2021.
And in the first 11 months, we
raised a little more than $100 million.
And the valuation was $1.5 billion.
So it took us actually roughly 11 months
to be precise to become a billion dollar.
Less than a year?
Yeah, less than a year.
That's crazy.
So do you think somebody can
get rich quick in today's world?
I think it's very easy if you, A, focus
on being at the right place and at the right
time.
And with the right place, I don't only mean location.
I also mean the industry to choose it.
So if I were to choose an industry in
the 1990s, late 1990s, I would choose the internet.
If I were to choose in
2010s, I would choose the social media.
And if you were to ask me which industry
would I choose now, either I would choose AI or
I would choose blockchain or Web3.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No, I was broke.
So basically, you know, I
came from a very humble family.
Starbucks coffee at one point in time when I
was 18 was luxury for me, you know, because
I was born in Delhi.
It was luxury.
So I didn't have any money.
But I think that's my biggest advantage because
when you come from nothing, you can only go
up.
You cannot go down.
The sky's the limit.
I think it's actually good to be broke
when you're starting up, you know, because you
realize the importance of money.
Even when you make a lot of money, you
don't spend that much money because you know the
importance of money.
What's the lesson about money that
banks don't want people to know?
They want you to invest
in fixed deposit, but you shouldn't.
Why?
Because that makes banks more money.
Banks make money on your money.
That's how banks get richer.
And that's how the rich keep getting richer.
Poor keep getting poorer.
And that's why I like blockchain.
And that's how I like crypto.
Because when you invest, it's your
own money turning into double, triple,
four times, and you're multiplying your own money.
And you know, if I'm sending you money
today in crypto, the transaction cost is about a
dollar.
Even if I send you
$10 million, I spend a dollar.
We send $10 million in
banking, spend a lot of money.
Yeah.
You brought up how the rich
get richer, the poor get poorer.
How can somebody escape that cycle of poverty?
That's why I'm saying get into Web3
because Web3 is the way to go.
If you get into it, you're escaping the
cycle because that's the only place where poor people
are turning into middle class, middle class
turning into upper middle class, upper middle
class turning into rich people
and getting wealthy and wealthy.
So.
This cycle, I've seen it in the last seven years.
I know my friends who were broke until 2020.
2021 bull run, they became millionaires.
2025 bull run, they'll become billionaires.
You know?
So it's, and 2025 is going to be
the biggest bull run crypto we'll ever see.
So you like crypto more than real estate?
I love crypto because it's liquid.
Real estate's not liquid.
If you own a property for say $15 million to
find a buyer, it'll take you a lot of time.
If you own $15 million in crypto,
one minute, you have your money out.
That was money right there, bro.
That was excellent.
Guys, that was incredible.
He built a billion dollar company in 11 months.
But one of the biggest reasons why he was
able to scale so quickly was because he raised
over a hundred million dollars from investors.
But I want to go even deeper because the only
way he was able to raise that kind of money
in that amount of time was how
effective and efficient his communication was when reaching
out to investors.
And that reminded me how much of a game
changer Grammarly has been for myself and my business.
And Grammarly isn't just a spelling or grammar tool.
It's an AI writing partner that works seamlessly.
With your everyday apps to
help you write better and faster.
For example, when I'm reaching out to the
biggest companies in the world and the biggest
entrepreneurs to do interviews, Grammarly helps
me craft the most professional and perfect
messages to send to these people
and help me close these interviews.
Grammarly is so good because it ensures
my tone matches the exact person I'm reaching
out to, whether I'm trying to
be formal or even just building rapport.
Plus, it saves me so much time by speeding
up my edits and cutting down on rewrites with
just a few clicks.
And the best part, all the
features I'm talking about are completely free.
You can sign up and take a
look at the links in the description.
Download Grammarly for free using my link, Grammarly.com slash Hard Knocks or go down
to the link in the description of this video or in the pinned comment.
So if you want to take your communication to the next level,
whether you're running a business or just starting out, Grammarly has you covered.
But with that being said, let's get this next interview.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, have you ever been broke before?
Many times.
Yeah.
And what line of business did you end up in?
I'm in tech in BC.
Venture capital.
Are you a business owner?
I run a bunch of tech companies.
Yeah.
How long have you been an entrepreneur?
17 years.
17 years?
And over these 17 years across all these companies, what was
the most amount of money that you made in a single year?
Many, many millions of dollars.
Could you give me a range?
Over 50.
Over 50, Bill.
And I go all over the
world interviewing the most successful entrepreneurs.
Could I get one quick minute
with you for the channel real quick?
Sure.
So who's the richest person that you've ever met?
I've met several billionaires.
One of them lives permanently in
Monaco at the Four Seasons Hotel.
He's from India and he runs a bunch of things in the tech
space as well and a bunch of other non-tech related stuff in real estate.
So what have you learned from networking?
With billionaires?
Don't talk about work.
What do you mean?
You want to talk to billionaires?
Get to know them personally.
Because you know why?
Everybody has no idea how to talk to billionaires.
But at the end of
the day, they're just people too.
So make friends.
Be a non-transactional person.
I want to talk to you.
I want to get to know you.
I want to get to know you and I
want to understand who you are as a person first.
Then we can be friends.
Then maybe we can do business together.
That's it.
Start humanizing the relationships first.
And then once you create a human to human
relationship with the wealthiest people, they'll take you everywhere.
People go into conversations with
a desire to achieve an outcome.
And that often gets in the
way of you getting to know people.
But the reality is the best businesses that have ever been built
have come out of a conversation that had nothing to do with business.
It had something to do with, hey, we have a shared desire of
being at this conference or being at this event or being at this party.
And then now we have
a shared common affinity towards something.
Okay, you look like a cool person.
I'm a cool person.
I think we align on values.
Let's go and build together.
What does that mean?
Who cares?
The worst ideas executed well are going
to outperform the best ideas executed poorly.
Do you know the guy that invented the Snuggie?
Do you know what I'm talking about?
The blanket with the sleeves?
Yeah.
$100 million in sales.
It's a blanket with sleeves.
Terrible idea executed well will always
trump the great idea executed poorly.
Full stop.
Are you a good salesman?
It's the best.
No, I never started off that way,
but you have to develop those skills.
I'm a computer science grad.
I've been programming my entire life.
So my life has actually been behind a computer screen.
But here's the other really important tip.
Life is too damn short to be shy.
Way too damn short to be shy.
And so most programmers, the geeks in us, they're all people that are
traditionally pretty introverted that like to be behind closed doors or behind screens.
That's not good enough.
You want to make it and
you want to make it big?
Run your mouth.
I love that.
Learn how to run your mouth.
A closed mouth does not get fed.
No, it does not.
And it keeps the air inside.
You got to open up.
We were just talking as well.
Like, even when I come to events like
these, it's nice to see the content and stuff.
But at the end of the day, what
I want to do is what we're doing.
I want to stand in line and meet people.
I want to go and grab a table, put a
bunch of coffees down, invite people and let's have a conversation.
Tony Hsieh, who's like the former CEO of Zappos, is
like one of like people that I respect the most.
Rest in peace.
He coined this term Collision Hours.
And so he developed Container City in Vegas, right, where you can go in and
just meet people and collide with them because that's what he wanted to do and create.
If we can get enough people with the right mindset to just take a moment to talk
to each other over a coffee, over a drink, over a shared initiative, that's where the magic happens.
That's how creation actually happens,
by creating these Collision Hours.
So create them.
Don't wait for them to happen.
You've got to create these Collision Hours for yourself.
Now, you said you did
over 50 million in a year.
How did you scale from seven to eight figures?
Like a lot of entrepreneurs, they got that great idea.
They start that business.
They struggle to scale and grow it.
What took you from making seven to eight figures?
You got to build the companies in
such a way that they're built for scale.
This is why we built tech.
Tech has infinite scale.
When you're building software, you don't
need to produce a physical good.
You're producing a digital good.
Selling digital goods is so
much easier than selling physical goods.
It then becomes all about
investing in your go-to-market strategy.
How do you get the right
types of people like you guys?
How do you get millions of followers on your channel?
Same thing with tech.
Find the product.
Find the solution that you're trying to solve for.
Create your go-to-market strategy.
Find the people online that are going to want to buy your product
and then scale it infinitely because then the world is your entire market.
That's a massive leap.
That's a masterclass right there.
What is the best sector of
tech to get into in today's world?
So you got to, we were just talking about this.
So you got to think about the problem that needs to be
solved in five years from now and invest in it from right now.
Close your eyes.
Imagine the world in the next five years.
What is it going to look like?
Are we going to be having robots walking amongst us?
Is it going to be flying cars?
Is it going to be that the doors are
going to talk to you in a certain way?
If that's the world that you imagine in
five years from now, build that technology today.
That's the way that you're
going to be able to scale.
Don't follow trends.
The trends are already built.
It's too late for you.
Otherwise, you're going to just be a copycat.
You want to really make a big impact.
Invest in deep tech.
Invest in the stuff that's going to happen in
five years from now and start building it today.
So what do you think that is?
Like, what do you think that
sector of tech is going to be?
Yeah, so that's going to be everything
around the future of AI and automation.
So think about the world where you're going to start working a lot less because now
robots and AI are going to dominate the way that we engage in our day-to-day setting.
What does that industry look like?
What is the periphery?
What does the thing that's going to power the robots?
How are we going to keep investing
in things like more and more optimized batteries?
How are we going to invest in making sure
that the machines are actually producing more and more batteries?
How are we going to keep producing
the results in an accurate format for you?
How are we going to provide more synthetic data
to train the machines on the next evolution of things?
What does the future of social media look like
for people that are producing content using AI avatars?
And so on and so forth.
Really just imagine the future state.
There's a great way of thinking about it as well.
Look at all the sci-fi movies.
What are people have already thought about
that you can now start inventing today?
What's the most profitable businesses
that you're investing in today's world?
Mortgage tech.
I know it sounds boring, but boring businesses
are really, really great businesses to invest in.
Mortgage technology.
Mortgage technology is really, at least with what's going on
in the economic craziness that's happening in North America right now.
That's probably our most profitable one right now.
We've got a couple of investments in the AI
space right now that are both going to get acquired.
And so they were purposely built to be acquired.
In your iPhone, the company that built the face
ID, they were specifically built for purpose of being acquired.
So we like that type of stuff.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much for your time.
You guys, we just interviewed a venture capital
and a tech mogul out here in Dubai.
And he just gave you guys a million
dollars worth of game in that last interview.
I can't count the amount of
gems he just gave you guys.
That was a business masterclass from a VC mogul.
Crazy interview out here in Dubai.
We got to go get this
next one and keep this video rolling.
Come on, let's go.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Is this your Rolls Royce?
Sure is.
And what do you do for living out here
in Dubai to be able to afford a Rolls Royce?
I run a blockchain company.
You run a blockchain company?
I sure do.
How long have you been a business owner?
Since I was a kid.
But this company for five years.
Over these five years, what was the most
amount of money you made in a single year?
Last year was $100 million.
You made $100 billion last year?
Yeah.
Was that for yourself or the business?
That's for myself. Plus on top,
the business made money as well.
Are you serious?
I'm serious.
I go all over the world
interviewing the most successful business owners.
Could I get one quick minute
with you for the channel real quick?
You're most welcome.
What is your net worth?
Maybe $300 million.
$300 million?
Yeah.
That's incredible.
As somebody who's worth a couple hundred million dollars,
what is the best financial advice that you ever received?
Look, first you have to make it.
You go all in on your
idea because you don't have money.
But when you have money, you have to be diversified.
That's very important to be balanced.
You cannot be too aggressive on one thing.
But when you're making it,
your first $100 million, just go for it.
You have to be crazy, insane, never giving up.
If they all leave my
office, if everyone wants to leave,
I go there and work overnight, right?
You just don't give up.
You just keep going, going, going.
Even if you don't have the
money, fake it till you make it.
Keep going.
You cannot give up.
And when you go broke, the first time
I went broke, I also worked in tech.
I didn't give up.
I learned a lot from it.
I was actually part of
the dot-com bubble in year 2000.
It was tough, right?
We lost everything.
We had a lot of great ideas.
But then I thought I have all the knowledge.
I know how Google works.
I know how Google ranks.
And I built Pocono.
I built news.com, which was the number
one site in the world for poker.
So you just do stuff that you learn from.
So if you lose money on
certain things, you don't give up.
You take the knowledge that you got from that experience,
and you go and create other stuff.
So money will always come to
you if you have what it takes.
Right.
What's the best investment somebody can make in 2025?
The best investment is just buy Sol.
What's Sol?
Solana blockchain.
Why?
Because it's the fastest,
cheapest transactions, most scalable,
and the best team.
What about Bitcoin?
Bitcoin's the god of blockchain, right?
And so it's different.
It's where you put most of your money.
You put most of your money in, and
then you put some in the other ones.
You cannot compare it.
Bitcoin is not working and doing transactions.
It's not having validators like Solana.
Solana doesn't take.
We don't need miners.
It's all already in a different level.
You're talking about a different
level of blockchain, 2.0, 3.0.
How many billionaires have you met?
I've met a lot of billionaires.
I don't count, but there's a lot.
In Dubai, there's a lot.
And I've met a lot in
America, a lot of interesting people.
Where are you from?
I grew up in Australia,
but I was born in Lithuania.
So what's the greatest
lesson you've learned about entrepreneurship?
You cannot be complacent.
And you have to keep developing.
And you have to get the
best people to work with you.
Henry Ford said, only with
a team you can make it.
So you need a good team together with you.
One person is nothing.
It's not about me.
Having a lot of shareholders,
happy shareholders, having a great team,
tech team, that's how we become successful.
People will take you places that money can't.
Exactly.
It's all about people.
It's all about talent.
And if you can get them to work
with you and build a bigger thing, that's success.
Did you have wealthy parents?
I had no wealthy parents.
I was born in the Soviet Union.
You know, we lost everything.
We had to come up from zero.
So you went from zero to 300M.
I went from zero to 300M.
That's incredible.
This is a lot of people's dream car.
A lot of people want
to own a Rolls Royce someday.
Give them one last message about
business, life, money that's not taught.
Trust yourself.
Just go for it yourself.
Do things you love.
And then if it becomes a
business, you're going to be very happy.
And key is to invest.
Invest, invest.
Don't save, but invest.
Invest in yourself, in your health, in your
head, and in the businesses you can invest.
In the stock market, in the blockchain, in the crypto.
Just invest all your life.
And you're going to have
the most interesting, successful life ever.
Whatever you're doing.
And not everybody has to be a business.
You can be a great investor.
Whatever you can afford to.
And you're going to have
the most interesting life, successful life.
And there's going to be so much
money to be made to enjoy it.
And there's going to be so much money to spend.
And that's going to be so
much money to invest in your life.
And that's going to be so much money to spend.
So I can't wait to see
you on the inside of the community.
And with that being said, I'll
see you in the next video.